Guide to the Everett Needham Case papers A1015
Special Collections and University Archives, Colgate University Libraries
- Poem. Case, Elizabeth Parker. "The Little 'Men in the Reds'.", 1922 (?) (Box 16, Folder 26)
- Case, Sammy. "Sammy's Judge of People.", undated (Box 16, Folder 27)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: Samuel Case., 1944 June 22 (Box 16, Folder 28)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: Samuel Case., 1944 May 2 (Box 16, Folder 29)
- Original letters from Adlai E. Stevenson to Everett N. Case., 1943-1962 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Adlai E. Stevenson Papers., 1943-1968 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: Mrs. J.H. Case, 1942 October 23 (Box 18, Folder 1)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: J.H. Case, 1940 May 15 (Box 18, Folder 2)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: J.H. Case, 1940 June 5 (Box 18, Folder 3)
- TN, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: J.H. Case, 1940 October 15 (Box 18, Folder 4)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: J.H. Case, 1940 October 22 (Box 18, Folder 5)
- TN, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: J.H. Case, 1941 April 12 (Box 18, Folder 6)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: J.H. Case, 1941 April 28 (Box 18, Folder 7)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: J.H. Case, 1941 June 10 (Box 18, Folder 8)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: J. Herbert Case, 1941 September 26 (Box 18, Folder 9)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: J.H. Case, 1942 February 25 (Box 18, Folder 10)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: J.H. Case, 1942 March 6 (Box 18, Folder 11)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: J.H. Case, 1942 March 18 (Box 18, Folder 12)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: J.H. Case, 1942 April 2 (Box 18, Folder 13)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: J.H. Case, 1942 April 4 (Box 18, Folder 14)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: J.H. Case, 1942 September 1 (Box 18, Folder 15)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: J.H. Case, 1942 September 10 (Box 18, Folder 16)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: Mrs. J.H. Case, 1942 October 5 (Box 18, Folder 17)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: JH. Case, 1942 November 13 (Box 18, Folder 18)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: J.H. Case, 1942 December 31 (Box 18, Folder 19)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: Mr. and Mrs. J.H. Case, 1943 January 13 (Box 18, Folder 20)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: Mrs. J.H. Case, 1943 February 10 (Box 18, Folder 21)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: J.H. Case, 1943 March 1 (Box 18, Folder 22)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: J.H. Case, 1943 May 31 (Box 18, Folder 23)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: Mrs. J.H. Case, 1943 June 4 (Box 18, Folder 24)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: Mrs. J.H. Case, 1943 July 6; 2 pages (Box 18, Folder 25)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: J.H. Case, 1943 July 17; 1 page (Box 18, Folder 26)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: J.H. Case, 1943 August 19; 2 pages (Box 18, Folder 27)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: Mrs. J.H. Case, 1943 August 24; 2 pages (Box 18, Folder 28)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: J.H. Case, 1943 September 22; 1 page (Box 18, Folder 29)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: J.H. Case, 1943 September 29; 1 page (Box 18, Folder 30)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: Mrs. J.H. Case, 1943 October 7; 2 pages (Box 18, Folder 31)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: J.H. Case, 1943 October 27; 1 page (Box 18, Folder 32)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: J.H. Case, 1943 November 9; 1 page (Box 18, Folder 33)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: Mrs. J.H. Case, 1943 December 7; 2 pages (Box 18, Folder 34)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: Mrs. J.H. Case, 1944 January 5; 1 page (Box 18, Folder 35)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: Mrs. J.H. Case, 1944 March 15; 1 page (Box 18, Folder 36)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: Mr. and Mrs. J.H. Case, 1944 March 31; 1 page (Box 18, Folder 37)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: Mrs. J.H. Case, 1944 April 6; 2 pages (Box 18, Folder 38)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: Mrs. J.H. Case, 1944 May 2; 2 pages (Box 18, Folder 39)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: J.H. Case, 1944 May 17; 1 page (Box 18, Folder 40)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: J.H. Case, 1944 June 19; 1 page (Box 18, Folder 41)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: Mr. and Mrs. J.H. Case, 1944 November 3; 1 page (Box 18, Folder 42)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: Mrs. J.H. Case, 1944 December 5; 1 page (Box 18, Folder 43)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1945 July 6; 1 page (Box 19, Folder 1)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1945 October 29; 2 pages (Box 19, Folder 2)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1945 November 6; 2 pages (Box 19, Folder 3)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1945 November 16; 1 page (Box 19, Folder 4)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1945 November 20; 1 page (Box 19, Folder 5)
- TN, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1945 December 13 (Box 19, Folder 6)
- TN, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1946 May 15 (Box 19, Folder 7)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1946 August 24; 1 page (Box 19, Folder 8)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1946 September 20; 1 page (Box 19, Folder 9)
- TN, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1946 November 9 (Box 19, Folder 10)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1947 January 8; 1 page (Box 19, Folder 11)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1947 July 7; 1 page (Box 19, Folder 12)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1947 November 3; 1 page (Box 19, Folder 13)
- TN, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1947 November 6 (Box 19, Folder 14)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1947 November 19; 1 page (Box 19, Folder 15)
- TN, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1948 April 21 (Box 19, Folder 16)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1948 October 5; 1 page (Box 19, Folder 17)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1949 October 5; 1 page (Box 19, Folder 18)
- TN, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1950 January 26 (Box 19, Folder 19)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1950 March 22; 1 page (Box 19, Folder 20)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1950 April 28; 3 pages (Box 19, Folder 21)
- TN, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1950 May 1 (Box 19, Folder 22)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1950 May 11; 2 pages (Box 19, Folder 23)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1950 May 22; 1 page (Box 19, Folder 24)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1950 June 21; 1 page (Box 19, Folder 25)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1950 December 1; 1 page (Box 19, Folder 26)
- TN, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1951 January 27 (Box 19, Folder 27)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1952 July 26; 2 pages (Box 19, Folder 28)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1952 October 2; 1 page (Box 19, Folder 29)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1952 October 15; 1 page (Box 19, Folder 30)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1952 December 20; 1 page (Box 19, Folder 31)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1953 April 6; 1 page (Box 19, Folder 32)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1954 May 17; 2 pages (Box 19, Folder 33)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: Elizabeth Case, 1954 June 22; 2 pages (Box 19, Folder 34)
- TL, unsigned. Case, Everett N. To: James Case, 1955 January 14; 3 pages (Box 19, Folder 35)
- TL, signed. Smitney, Stephen J. To: Owen Young, 1942 April 15; 1 page (Box 20, Folder 1)
- TL, signed. Smitney, Stephen J. To: Charles F. Adams, 1942 April 17; 1 page (Box 20, Folder 2)
- TL, signed. Smitney, Stephen J. To: Everett N. Case, 1942 April 17; 1 page (Box 20, Folder 3)
- TL, signed. Smitney, Stephen J. To: W.W. Trench, 1942 April 22; 1 page (Box 20, Folder 4)
- TN, Signed. Smitney, Stephen J. To: Everett N. Case, 1942 April 23; 1 page (Box 20, Folder 5)
- TL, signed. Smitney, Stephen J. To: F.D. Reed, 1942 April 27; 1 page (Box 20, Folder 6)
- TL, unsigned. Smitney, Stephen J. To: Owen D. Young, 1942 April 27; 1 page (Box 20, Folder 7)
- TL, signed. Smitney, Stephen J. To: Owen D. Young, 1942 April 27; 1 page (Box 20, Folder 8)
- TL, signed. Smitney, Stephen J. To: George B. Cutten, 1942 May 4; 2 pages (Box 20, Folder 9)
- TL, signed. Smitney, Stephen J. To: George B. Cutten, 1942 May 4; 2 pages (Box 20, Folder 10)
- TL, signed. Smitney, Stephen J. To: George B. Cutten, 1942 May 11; 1 page (Box 20, Folder 11)
- TL, signed. Smitney, Stephen J. To: George B. Cutten, 1942 May 11; 1 page (Box 20, Folder 12)
- TL, signed. Smitney, Stephen J. To: Everett N. Case, 1942 May 11; 1 page (Box 20, Folder 13)
- TL, signed. Smitney, Stephen J. To: Everett N. Case, 1942 May 11; 1 page (Box 20, Folder 14)
- TL, signed. Smitney, Stephen J. To: James C. Colgate, 1942 May 18; 1 page (Box 20, Folder 15)
- TL, signed. Smitney, Stephen J. To: William M. Parks, 1942 May 29; 1 page (Box 20, Folder 16)
- TL, signed. Smitney, Stephen J. To: Stephen T. Early, 1942 June 25; 1 page (Box 20, Folder 17)
- TL, signed. Smitney, Stephen J. To: James M. Mead, 1942 July 8; 1 page (Box 20, Folder 18)
- TL, signed. Smitney, Stephen J. To: A. A. Berle, Jr., 1942 July 10; 1 page (Box 20, Folder 19)
- TL, signed. Smitney, Stephen J. To: Charles F. Adams, 1942 July 10; 1 page (Box 20, Folder 20)
- TL, signed. Smitney, Stephen J. To: Caroline O'Day, 1942 July 28; 1 page (Box 20, Folder 21)
- TL, signed. Smitney, Stephen J. To: Josephine Young Case, 1942 July 28; 1 page (Box 20, Folder 22)
- Everett Needham Case Biography, undated; 2 pages (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Newspaper Clippings on the Election of Everett N. Case as Colgate President, 1942 February 19 - 1942 July 23; 21 pages (Box 21, Folder 2)
- Newspaper articles on issues President Case sought to work on, 1942 August 15 - 1942 January 24; 29 pages (Box 21, Folder 3)
- Itinerary for Dr. and Mrs. Everett Case, 1958 August 30; 3 pages (Box 21, Folder 4)
- Article on American Liberal Colleges by Everett N. Case. Harvard Alumni Bulletin, 1942 May 16; 1 page (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Newspaper article on engagements of Everett N. Case's children, 1956 March 24 and 1957 November 7; 2 pages (Box 21, Folder 6)
- Newspaper article on the wedding of Everett N. Case's son, 1964 August 6; 1 page (Box 21, Folder 7)
- Death of Mrs. J.H. Case, mother of Everett N. Case, 1957 October 10; 1 page (Box 21, Folder 8)
- Newspaper article on Josephine Y. Case's novel, 1945 February 6; 2 pages (Box 21, Folder 9)
- "Our Aims and Ideals" by Everett N. Case, undated; 1 page (Box 21, Folder 10)
- "Crystal Vase", Undated; 1 photograph (Box 21, Folder 11)
- Correspondence between Robert V. Smith and Steuben Glass regarding gift for Case, 1962 February 13 - May 4; 4 pages (Box 21, Folder 12)
- "Emily Again" by Josephine Young Case, undated; 6 pages (Box 21, Folder 13)
- Remarks of President Everett Case at Students' Association Meeting, 1955 February 25; 12 pages (Box 21, Folder 14)
- Newspaper Articles on Everett Case's Election as President of Colgate University, 1942 February 6 - March 2; 12 pages (Box 21, Folder 15)
- Founders' Day Address, 1955 September 21; 8 pages (Box 21, Folder 16)
- Founders' Day Address, 1956 September 24; 6 pages (Box 21, Folder 17)
- Newspaper Articles on Everett Case, 1942February - 1947 December; 14 pages (Box 21, Folder 18)
- "Genealogy of Young Families of Mohawk Valley Published". The Dolgeville Republican., 1947 July 17; 1 page (Box 21, Folder 19)
- "The Independent College in an Interdependent World" by Everett N. Case., 1947 January; 6 pages (Box 21, Folder 20)
- Photographs of Everett Case, Undated; 30 photographs (Box 21, Folder 21)
- Photographs of Everett Case, undated; 16 photographs (Box 21, Folder 22)
- Photographs of Everett Case, undated; 34 photographs (Box 21, Folder 23)
- Negatives of Everett Case, undated (Box 21, Folder 24)
- Envelope containing photograph of Everett N. Case, undated; 1 photograph (Box 21, Folder 25)
- Photographs of Everett Case, undated; 25 photographs (Box 21, Folder 26)
- Photograph of J. Herbert Case, undated; 1 photograph (Box 21, Folder 27)
- Photograph of James and Josephine Case, Everett Case's children, undated; 1 photograph (Box 21, Folder 28)
- Photograph of Ralph G. Gould with his wife and son, undated; 1 photograph (Box 21, Folder 29)
- Photograph of Mrs. Everett Case, undated; 1 photograph (Box 21, Folder 30)
- "Must Vacate! Lease Expired!" Postcard Invitation, undated; 1 page (Box 21, Folder 31)
- "Institutional Integrity" Address by Everett Case, 1960 October 7; 12 pages (Box 21, Folder 32)
- Address at the Brown University Chapel by Everett N. Case, 1942 November 24; 4 pages (Box 21, Folder 33)
- Address to Colgate University's Graduating Class by Everett N. Case, 1942 December 13; 7 pages (Box 21, Folder 34)
- "College Education After the War" Radio Discussion, 1942 November 17; 9 pages (Box 21, Folder 35)
- Statement by Everett Case before a Colgate vs. Duke football game, 1942 October 17; 3 pages (Box 21, Folder 36)
- Inauguration Address by Everett Case, 1942 September 24; 19 pages (Box 21, Folder 37)
- Draft letter to Commander P. and his staff, 1943 January 14; 2 pages (Box 21, Folder 38)
- "The Milk Situation" Radio Talk by Everett Case, 1943 February 6; 6 pages (Box 21, Folder 39)
- Founders' Day Address by Everett Case, 1943 February 25; 7 pages (Box 21, Folder 40)
- "The Capital Levy and the Colleges" Address by Everett N. Case, 1943 March 5; 10 pages (Box 21, Folder 41)
- Statement by President Everett Case for the New York Times, 1943 April 18 (Box 21, Folder 42)
- Founders' Day Address by Everett Case, 1943 May 8; 13 pages (Box 21, Folder 43)
- NEWS from Colgate University, undated; 5 pages (Box 21, Folder 44)
- Convocation Address by Everett N. Case, 1943 April 29; 7 pages (Box 21, Folder 45)
- "The Double Challenge to the College" Address by Everett Case, 1942 October 1; 7 pages (Box 21, Folder 46)
- Convocation Address, 1942 September 10; 5 pages (Box 21, Folder 47)
- "The Crisis in Education" Address by Everett Case, 1943 March 21; 11 pages (Box 21, Folder 48)
- Photograph of Everett N. Case at the Annual Meeting of the American Council on Education, 1952 May; 1 photograph (Box 21, Folder 49)
- Invitations to events hosted at the President's house, undated; 12 pages (Box 21, Folder 50)
- "Get Acquainted Dinner" Programs, 1942 October 8 (Box 21, Folder 51)
- The Annual Block C Banquet Program, 1961 December 5; 8 pages (Box 21, Folder 52)
- Photograph of Josephine Young Case's book, This Very Tree, undated; 1 photograph (Box 21, Folder 53)
- "La Belle Dame Sans Souci" Poem by Everett Case, undated; 2 pages (Box 21, Folder 54)
- Letter and Report by the Association of Colleges and Universities, 1950 December 12; 7 pages (Box 21, Folder 55)
- "Let's Stump the Experts" Scene 1 Script, 1949 December 6; 1 page (Box 21, Folder 56)
- "Written in Sand" by Josephine Young Case. Pamphlet, undated; 2 pages (Box 21, Folder 57)
- Article written for the Alumni News, 1962 February; 10 pages (Box 21, Folder 58)
- Blank stationary for the Colgate President, undated; 4 pages (Box 21, Folder 59)
- "Colgate Takes the High Road" Founders' Day Address by Everett Case, 1956 September 24; 6 pages (Box 21, Folder 60)
- "Our Aims and Ideals" A statement by Everett N. Case, undated; 2 pages (Box 21, Folder 61)
- Letter from Thomas Alva Bartlett to Everett N. Case, 1969 August 5; 1 page (Box 21, Folder 62)
- Miscellaneous newspaper clippings, undated; 15 pages (Box 21, Folder 63)
- "Cross-the-Country Luncheon of Colgate University Alumni and Friends" Pamphlet, 1944 March 4; 1 page (Box 21, Folder 64)
- "Not by the Sword Alone" Address by Everett Case, 1943 May 26; 11 pages (Box 21, Folder 65)
- "Education for a Lasting World Peace" by Everett N. Case, 1945 April 5; 10 pages (Box 21, Folder 66)
- "The Principle of Order" Address by Everett N. Case, 1960 September 15; 10 pages (Box 21, Folder 67)
- Address to the Graduating Class by Everett N. Case, 1945 February 23; 9 pages (Box 21, Folder 68)
- Correspondence regarding the election of Everett N. Case as President, 1941 December - 1942 February; 30 pages (Box 21, Folder 69)
- The Inauguration of Everett N. Case, 1942 September 24 (Box 21, Folder 70)
- Founders' Day Convocation Programs, 1946 September 26 and 1947 September 24; 2 pages (Box 21, Folder 71)
- Phi Beta Kappa Initiation and Reception Pamphlets, 1942 November 11; 2 pages (Box 21, Folder 72)
- Faculty Information on Physical Education and Athletics, undated; 2 pages (Box 21, Folder 73)
- Faculty Consultation on Religion in Higher Education, undated; 3 pages (Box 21, Folder 74)
- Colgate University Performances, undated; 3 pages (Box 21, Folder 75)
- "Colgate-in-the-War-Dinner" Notice, 1943 February 18; 2 pages (Box 21, Folder 76)
- Naval Flight Prep School Information Sheet, undated; 1 page (Box 21, Folder 77)
- Chapel Events, undated; 2 pages (Box 21, Folder 78)
- Article by Everett N. Case in the Harvard Alumni Bulletin, 1942 May 16; 1 page (Box 21, Folder 79)
- Invitation to attend an "informal tunk", 1942 December 4; 1 page (Box 21, Folder 80)
- "A Story of Indium" by Sidney J. French, 1934 May; 2 pages (Box 21, Folder 81)
- Addresses and Articles by Everett N. Case, 1942 - 1945 September 8 (Box 21, Folder 82)
- Everett N. Case Addresses and Articles, 1945 September 24 - 1947 December 8 (Box 21, Folder 83)
- Everett N. Case Addresses and Articles, 1948 March 3 - 1949 December 6 (Box 21, Folder 84)
- Everett N. Case Addresses and Articles, 1950 January 12 - 1954 January (Box 21, Folder 85)
- Everett N. Case Addresses and Articles, 1954 May 4 - 1957 November 21 (Box 21, Folder 86)
- Everett N. Case Addresses and Articles, 1958 February 3 - 1962 June 11 (Box 21, Folder 87)
- Everett N. Case Speeches, 1962 December 12 - 1969 June 1 (Box 21, Folder 88)
- Photographs of Everett N. Case, undated; 3 photographs (Box 21, Folder 89)
- "Get Acquainted Dinner", 1942 October 8; 2 photographs (Box 21, Folder 90)
- Photographs of Everett N. Case, undated; 6 photographs (Box 21, Folder 91)
- Photographs of Everett Case, undated; 3 photographs (Box 21, Folder 92)
- Address by Everett N. Case to graduating class, 1943 December 21; 2 pages (Box 21, Folder 93)
- Table of contents to unknown volumes, 1942-1962; 8 pages (Box 21, Folder 94)
- Letters to and from Adlai Stevenson, 1952-1960 (Box 22)
- Josephine Younf Case papers, 1900-2000 (Box 23)